Guide to the Branner Hall resident fellow records SC1139
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Branner Hall resident fellow records
1954-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Branner Hall
SC1139
20 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
Scope and Contents
Materials include posters, yearbooks, directories, literary magazines, event flyers, and resident advisor information and handbooks. Posters and flyers from events and performances include "Branner Presents" speaker events, original musical and theatrical productions, and film screenings. "Branner Presents" talks are led by faculty, authors, scientists, celebrities, social activists, public servants, and many other noteworthy speakers.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to Stanford University, Special Collections by current resident fellows in the Summer of 2011; 2017.
Biographical/Historical note
As of 2012, Branner Hall is an upperclass (non-frosh) residence with a focus program on public service. In previous years, Branner Hall was an all-freshman dormitory. Opened in January 1924, Branner Hall was named after John Caspar Branner, Stanford’s first professor, second president (1913-1915), and Chair of the Department of Geology and Mining. The elegant building was designed by the San Francisco firm of Bakewell & Brown, who also designed Memorial Auditorium and the original Bing Wing of Green Library.
College students -- California -- Stanford.; Dormitory life -- California -- Stanford; Cochran, Johnnie L.; Tan, Amy; Chase, Sylvia; Stanford University. Branner Hall; Schultz, George; Meese, Edwin
- Records, Accession ARCH-2011-188
  - Posters
    - Miscellaneous event posters (Box 1)
    - Bobbi Brown Visit, February 26 (Box 5)
    - Chinua Achebe Visit, 1988 Feb 16 (Box 5)
    - Governor Harold Stassen - Stanford Law Forum, April 14 (Box 5)
    - Meeting of "Da Gang" to Discuss "Da Big Plan", 1982 Nov 29 (Box 5)
    - Armistead Maupin Visit- Gay and Lesbian Awareness Week, 1983 May 5 (Box 5)
    - Congressman William Gray Visit, 1985 Sept 27 (Box 5)
    - Joan Baez Visit, 1985 Oct 1 (Box 5)
    - McGeorge Bundy Visit, 1985 Feb 18 (Box 5)
    - A Little Nonsense Publication - The unedited Chronicles of Branner Hall, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Dreams of the Future Discussion, November 29 (Box 5)
    - Memories to Kennell from Tina (Box 5)
    - Picture of Branner Hall RFs, 2006 Sep (Box 5)
    - Picture of Kennell A Jackson Jr. - Professor of History, circa 2005 (Box 5)
    - Dr. Robert J Lang visit, March 11 (Box 5)
    - Dr. Denise Clark Pope Visit, January 29 (Box 5)
    - Commencement, 1987 Jun (Box 5)
    - Amy Tan and Kaye Gibbons Visit, September 25 (Box 5)
    - Branner Presents: 2 Weeks of Fun and Contention (3 copies) (Box 5)
    - Branner R.A. Commencement Party, 1985 Jun 15 (Box 5)
    - "What's at Stake in '84" - Presidential Election panels, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Dr. Paul MacCready visits, January 22 (Box 5)
    - Gwendolyn Brooks visit, 1986 Oct 18 (Box 5)
    - The 60s - Retrospect on Revolution (Box 5)
    - The Big Thrill Poster, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Max Mathews, Jean Claude Risset, John Chowning Seminar and Concert (Box 5)
    - Philippe Manoury - En Echo, Sheet music, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Forgetting Tiburon: Asian American Theater Project, 2011 (Box 5)
    - Korean Culture Night (Box 5)
    - Seriously's Heart Tour - Chaos Theory Music, April 12 (Box 5)
    - Korean Movie Festival, March 1-2 (Box 5)
    - Korean Culture Night, May 4 (Box 5)
    - The Art of Waiting Play by Rob Shin, 2004 May 27-28 (Box 5)
    - Asian Pacific Islander Heritage Month, 2000 (Box 5)
    - R&L play by Takeo Rivera, May 1-4 (Box 5)
    - Stanford Living Wage Campaign (Box 5)
    - R&L play by Takeo Rivera (2nd copy) (Box 5)
    - Peter Shaffer's Black Comedy, January 24-26 (Box 5)
    - Asian Pacific Islander Heritage Month, 2008 May (Box 5)
    - Asian Pacific Islander Heritage Month, 1997 (Box 5)
    - East Fest - Celebration of East Asian Culture, 1985 Nov 8 (Box 5)
    - War Lily - Stanford Vietnamese Student Association, 2013 Apr 14 (Box 5)
    - Photograph of Hofstadter (Box 5)
  - Event flyers (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - R.A. informational pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Branner production programs (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Branner Sucks!" letter, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scavenger Hunt, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Scavenger Hunt, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sand sculpture (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Skits (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Skits (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Branner Journal (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Branner Quotes, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Branner Literary Magazines (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "The Branner Banner" (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Branner Directories, 1980s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - R.A. Staff Handbook (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - R.A. Staff Handbooks (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Yearbooks
    - Branner Yearbook, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - Branner Yearbook, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
    - Branner Yearbook, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
    - Branner Yearbook, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Branner Yearbook, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - Branner Yearbook, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
    - Branner Yearbook, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - B.I.M.M. (Branner's Interactive Multimedia Magazine), 1995; 1 optical disc(s) (cd-rom) (Box 4)
  - sex, lies, and civ books, an original musical., 1993; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
- Additional Posters, Accession ARCH-2018-075
  - Bill Baird "The Politics of Government and Sex: Why Abortion and Birth Control Must Remain Legal", 1984 May 16 (Box 1)
  - Sand Castle by Happy Branner People and Jerry Kirk, 1987 Mar 7 (Box 2)
  - Donald Kennedy "What Charles Darwin Discovered on His Trip to the Galapagos Islands", 1986 Oct 14 (Box 2)
  - Condoleezza Rice Coit Blacker "U.S. - Soviet Relations: What's the Next Move?", Oct 18 (Box 3)
  - Kennell Jackson introducing Ishmael Reed (Box 3)
  - Seymour Hersh "The Journalist and American Power", Nov 28 (Box 3)
  - Martin Anderson "American Economic Recovery and Policy Formulation", Oct 11 (Box 4)
  - Stanford vs. Oregon State, 1985 Oct 9 (Box 4)
  - Spike Lee and Monty Ross, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Donald Kennedy "The Reagan Library Complex", Dec 1 (Box 6)
  - Kennell Jackson - Arbiter of 4am Dispute, 1987 Spring (Box 7)